Guide to the George B. Harrison Papers, 1821-1924
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
George B. Harrison papers 1821-1924
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Harrison, George B.
18 Linear Feet 13,488 Items
Lawyer, of Clarke Co., Va.
Correspondence, daybooks, and family, business, and other papers. The bulk of the collection consists of cancelled checks, bills and receipts, legal papers, newspaper clippings, and advertisements. The papers deal with Civil War destruction in Virginia, social life in Virginia after the war, American interest in Cuba (1869-1870), agriculture and land in Florida (1880s), social, political, and economic activities in Clarke Co., the genealogy of the Harrison family, and other matters. Correspondents include Thomas R. Dew and Harry F. Byrd.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The George B. Harrison Papers were purchased by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1954.
Collection Overview
Correspondence, daybooks, and family, business, and other papers. The bulk of the collection consists of cancelled checks, bills and receipts, legal papers, newspaper clippings, and advertisements. Topics include Civil War destruction in Virginia, social life in Virginia after the war, American interest in Cuba (1869-1870), agriculture and land in Florida (1880s), social, political, and economic activities in Clarke Co., the genealogy of the Harrison family, and other matters. Correspondents include Thomas R. Dew and Harry F. Byrd.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Byrd, Harry Flood, 1887-1966
Dew, Thomas R. (Thomas Roderick), 1802-1846
Agriculture -- Florida
Lawyers -- Correspondence
Lawyers -- Virginia -- Clarke County
Clarke County (Va.)--Social conditions
Cuba -- Foreign relations -- United States
Florida -- Economic conditions
United States -- Foreign relations -- Cuba
United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Destruction and pillage
Virginia -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865
Virginia -- Social life and customs
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence Series, 1825-1924 and undated, (14 boxes)
  - 1882-1885 (Box 1)
  - undated (Box 2)
  - 1877-1881 (Box 3)
  - 1825-1876 (Box 4)
  - 1886-1888 (Box 5)
  - 1889-1896 (Box 6)
  - 1897-1902 (Box 7)
  - 1903-1906 (Box 8)
  - 1907-1908 (Box 9)
  - 1912-1913 (Box 10)
  - 1909-1911 (Box 11)
  - 1914-1915 (Box 12)
  - 1916-1920 (Box 13)
  - 1921-1924 and undated (Box 15)
- Legal Papers Series, 1821-1922 and undated, (7 boxes)
  - 1821-1879 (Box 2)
  - undated (Box 14)
  - 1880-1899 (Box 16)
  - 1900-1905 (Box 17)
  - 1906-1910 (Box 18)
  - 1911-1915 (Box 19)
  - 1916-1922 and undated (Box 21)
- Financial Papers Series, 1850-1924 and undated, (7 boxes)
  - 1850-1879 (Box 14)
  - 1880s (Box 20)
  - 1910-1919 (Box 22)
  - 1920-1924 and undated (Box 23)
  - 1880s-1899 (Box 25)
  - 1900-1909 (Box 26)
  - 1910-1919 (Box 27)
- Printed Material Series, (3 boxes)
  - Miscellany (Box 24)
  - Printed Material (Box 24, 30-31)
- Volumes Series, (3 boxes)
  - Volumes (Box 28-29, 32)
    [For locations of volumes F:6443, F:6454, F:6455, F:6456, please consult with a reference archivist.]